was invited. I gained 35 pounds in
prison because I they had a crooked
guard on on the payroll and he would he
would smuggle in, you know, pork loin
and white wine for the Marsala sauce and
mushrooms and tomatoes and pasta and
>> we feasted every single night. But I I
went to I ate with the Italians in the
cafeteria. We had dinners in in their
their cells in the evenings. We went to
I went to all of their parties, their
birthday celebrations. I even went to
the mafia Super Bowl party of all
things. They were great. And and the
funny thing is there's kind of a
postcript to this.
>> So I this this guy, he became my best
friend in the prison and still is one of
my best friends today. We talk all the
time. So it's about
>> Is he out?
>> He's out.
>> Yeah. Good.
>> Um Well, that's what the story's about.
He had gotten triple life without parole
for a firsttime nonviolent drug offense.
>> And so co Congress passed the um the uh
second chance act I think is what it was
called. And I'm I'm reading the paper. I
mean I'm sitting in his cell and I'm
reading the paper and I said, "Buddy,
have you read this article?" And he
said, "No." I said, "This is about you.
It's saying that you're eligible for
this new federal program." and he said,
'I'm not I'm not smart enough to to even
figure out how to do something like
that. I said, 'I'll write the appeal.'
So, I wrote his appeal. I sent it to the
Justice Department and I was released
from the prison just a couple of weeks
later.
I got out in February. His mother calls
me in August and she's crying. And I
said, "Oh my god, what happened to
Mark?" And she said, "No, no, it's good
news. They're letting him go." And I
said, "They're letting him go." And she
said, "The appeal you wrote, he won."
>> Wow.
>> I was like, "Oh my god, he told me when
he got out that that he owes that that
he owes me his life." And I said,
"Nonsense." I said, "You got screwed."
And all you needed was was for things to
come together at the right time for the
Justice Department to to acknowledge
that you got screwed. And as funny as it
sounds,
he applied for a real estate license.
And if you're a convicted felon, you
can't have a real estate license. So he
wrote to the governor and he said,
"Listen, I got screwed and Obama gave me
a commutation and I'm a good guy and,
you know, nonviolent and all this stuff.
Can I have a real estate license? And
the governor gave it to him and now he
is the number one selling real estate
agent at the Jersey Shore.
>> Isn't that great?
>> Lives in a a stunning house. Tons of
friends. He's just an awesome.
>> That's so awesome. That's so awesome. I
love to hear things like that.
>> Yeah. Good guy.
>> Unbelievable. You know, I mean, the
timing like you said, but if you did not
know him and if you did not read that,
he might still be there today.
>> You know,
there were eight people in his
conspiracy.
He was the only one who left the
conspiracy. He said, "This drug thing is
not for me. I quit." And he he quit. He
was the only one that did. And everybody
got arrested by the Drug Enforcement
Administration. and they offered
everybody deals and he said, "I'm not a
rat. I can't rat people out." And so he
didn't take the deal, not knowing that
everybody else took the deal. So the
other seven guys got five and a half
years and he got triple life without
parole.
>> Yeah.
>> My god, there must you just must feel
like your life is totally over. I bet
he's I bet he's extremely grateful every
day.
>> It's It's a new life. And I'm so happy
for him.
>> Yeah, great story.
>> He didn't deserve that treatment.
>> Right. Well, that's that's really Thank
you so much for sharing all this with
us. Now, we're going to try to get back
to the UFO topic somehow.
>> And uh but this is all really
fascinating. So I I just uh someone sent
me a um a a friend of basically the show
here and also a friend mutual friend of
Chris um
>> ah
>> uh he sent me this thing about this guy
talking about government secrets and it
had to do with Neil deGrasse Tyson and
two other people there in an interview
and the guy basically said that hey uh
the government leaks things all the
time. That's how they get funding
>> constantly.
>> So, and and so then the question came
up, well, why aren't they leaking about
the crash retrievals or the UFOs or
things like that? So, I guess I have to
ask you, what is your thoughts about um
that whole thing?
>> I I actually have thought about that and
you know, having been in the CIA for 15
years and and having been read into
special compartmented programs, I can
only conclude that these things are so
compartmentalized. so stovepiped
that there are too few people who
actually are read into the program to
leak it.
>> You know, this is this is how torture
didn't leak for so long. In the in the
beginning, there were only 16 people in
the entire federal government who knew
about the torture program.
>> Well, you know, later on it was it was
hundreds of people. There were dozens
that were actually carrying out the
torture.
>> That's really I mean I just it just hit
me that's so baffling that there's that
few people you know I mentioned earlier
about meeting with the two gentlemen
retired FBI and retired CIA right and we
we got into 911 you know talking to the
FBI and he talked about yes everything
is stovepiped and that's why the
information was protected and not enough
people there's not enough connections.
>> That's a very nice way to put it. The
the truth is that the CIA and the FBI
have hated each other since 1947
when the CIA was created. And so
the CIA knew that the hijackers were in
were in the United States and didn't
tell the FBI because the CIA wanted to
make a run at them and try to recruit
them. The FBI knew that there were
hijackers who were trying to get into
the United States but didn't tell the
CIA that they knew the identities of the
hijackers.
And so because because they refused to
cooperate
to the point where the CIA and FBI
computer systems were not even
compatible.
>> That's why 911 happened.
>> Yeah. And you came in right about that
time, right?
>> Oh, no. I was already I was already a
senior officer by 911.
>> Now I thought I thought you mentioned in
the interview that we did that they were
like getting ready to throw money into
all types anything
>> after after 911.
>> After 911 I got it. Yeah.
>> Yeah. I I had a uh I had a uh an idea
for an operation just a couple of weeks
after 911, a counterterrorism operation.
So, I went up to the director of the
counterterrorism center, Ambassador
Kofer Black, and I said, "Uh, Kofer,
I've got a I've got an operation that I
want to pass by you." And he put up his
hands and he said, "Whatever it is, just
do it. I have so much money, I can't
possibly spend it all."
>> And so, I was on the next plane.
>> That's amazing. That's amazing. But,
wow. Um, so do you think, um, this is
just from being, you know, involved? I
know that you there was no UFO, you
know, I know the CIA is is like foreign,
you know, there it's all foreign
>> foreign intelligence
>> and then FBI is, you know, American
>> domestic
>> basically domestic. Yes. But um um there
wouldn't be any case where the CIA would
be involved with any type of
>> Well, it's possible. It's possible.
>> Now, I'm going to run a scenario by you
like to say if perhaps like David Grush
mentioned, he thinks there is crash uh
UFOs reverse engineering. Say that
>> that would be it.
>> That would be it.
>> Yeah.
>> If if they could develop something that
could be dangerous to us somehow.
The CIA would never have the lead on
something like that. DARPA would have
the lead,
>> right?
>> They would bring in CIA and maybe one or
two other um agencies, probably DoD
agencies to come in and reverse engineer
something like that. But yeah, the CIA
would never have the uh would never have
the lead.
I used to work for this deputy director
of the CIA. Um good guy, but he always
used to h have this mantra. He would
always say, "The job of the CIA is to
recruit spies to steal secrets."
And I used to think, "Yeah, that's
technically true, but we also, you know,
fly around the world and murder people
and overthrow governments and, you know,
>> it's not just recruiting spies to steal
secrets." Although I get the sentiment.
>> Yeah. Yeah, but
>> I mean I can't even understand the how
something like that works. you know
where
that who decides what is you know we
have to watch this country we have to
watch that country this person may take
over that may fall you know we have to
get someone in there and you know I mean
who can figure all this stuff out with
such
>> and that's why that's why it fails so
often
>> and and you know one of the one of the
downsides too uh downsides to doing
proactive um operations like that
they're called covert action programs uh
is that and I think this is probably
human nature but the CIA always always
underestimates the level of blowback.
Blowback are the unintended consequences
for carrying out an operation.
So
for example, for example,
um I was the notetaker in a principal
committee meeting the night before we
invaded Iraq. and princip the principles
are the president, the vice president,
secretary of state, secretary of
defense, national security adviser,
director of the CIA and the um synet the
uh uh commander-in-chief of uh central
command. So um
my job was to sit silently behind the
CIA director and just take notes. One of
the senior officials from the from the
White House said at the end of the
meeting like he couldn't wait for
tomorrow because tomorrow we're going to
invade Iraq. And he said, "As soon as we
cross that border, they're going to
throw flowers at us."
And I said to the director afterwards,
"Do these people know nothing about the
Middle East? Do they know nothing about
history?
The Iraqis are going to see us as
foreign invaders and occupiers. They're
going to throw bombs, not flowers.
And sure enough,
>> really
>> threw bombs.
>> Oh god.
>> And then and then we're mired in a in a
war for, you know, more than a decade.
>> Another war.
>> Well, this is Jack who I was just
talking about, a mutual friend of uh
Chris Leos. So here's the question here
and I have to read this out because of
the audio part of the show. Considering
your experience as a whistleblower and
challenges you faced, what advice would
you give to individuals who possess
credible information about UAPs and who
are considering coming forward? Good
question, Jack.
>> That's a that's a very good question and
it's an important question.
So I I would highly recommend that you
consult with an attorney who specializes
in whistleblower rights. There are a
bunch of them here in Washington. They
may be a little bit harder to find
outside of Washington, but um you need
somebody who who's going to understand
where you're coming from and is going to
protect your your rights and and also
also protect you from overstepping so
that you know the the FBI can't come in
and ruin your life or the defense
department or the CIA or who whoever
else. So, absolutely consult an attorney
before you say anything at all publicly
and make sure that the attorney is there
when you're making the revelation.
You'll never ever regret doing that.
>> Now, uh I believe David Grush went about
it the right way as far as I know. I
don't know how much you know about that.
Yeah.